Hello everyone, welcome back to today's post grade school tutors. So today we are going to explore
for part of the data from the post grade school table. I was in for the data statement. Okay,
so basically here the latest statement in the post grade school is used to remove for
on or more low from the table based on the certain condition and it's a powerful tool for
managing the data in our database and just let's explore for how it works with some example.
Okay, so here in this session, so now first of all here I can just create for the example for
deleting row based on the condition. Okay, so you can specify the conditions to selectively
delete row from the table using the this function. Okay, so I can just go for here. First of all,
select the tables. So now first I can define for the delete statement to delete.
Run and here I can choose for now just going for the post grade school and in this insert,
I can choose for the article table. Okay, so now just, it is the article table. Okay,
and then going to the next step. So choose for here, we can use first, use this and
going for the article inside and here I can choose for the column name for the article title. Okay,
so now just go for here and then type the where the article title. So the
article underscore this title and it's equal to so here use for the title to the first slide.
So now open for the other query and here I can select the posture from the article table. Okay,
so here now just go here and create this is where so open for another. So now just create the
semicolon. Okay, so now get the semicolon the article table and now just execute and you can see
here select this and delete query. We can just select this point. So now just go and here I can type
this the delete and then use the delete query statement and now here I can select and execute
and just do it. So here I can just press the execute and now enter it is perfectly required. So
now open for disowned articles and now see here I have completely removed for the delete query
and article ID for six. So now just verify so now perfectly it will stop query. So now select
and you can see perfectly removed for delete the do your code. Okay, so here the
the null state for the table is not sure for the direct so here the double click you can see
the delete query and the article ID for six and here the double article step okay and
next we can say here the create and deleting for all the rows from a table. Okay, so you can use
for the delete statement all rows are now just go for here and then remove this and this now and
now not use or I'll also first of all here use for the delete one here article table okay.
So now just simply can here select and then execute and you can see here it is completely
affected. So now just go here and I can just verify this and result error because we have already
deleted the article table okay. So now you can see here the row which is completely random okay
so I hope you understand it. So here the confirmation message for the post grace query return here
the confirmation message okay. So you can choose for another table there is now right so
and I can use another example so now just delete a customer with the ID okay. So here I can use
for another table so here you can see here where now here it is called the companion table okay.
So here I can click for the table and now here I can just go into select and execute
and you can see here this is here see for the called the companion table or the record okay.
So I will use it perfectly at this time and here I can apply for the delete statement okay.
So here I can just go and now I can just delete the component and now I can type this delete
from the companion table and then start for this is the where for ID use equal to two okay.
So you can see here the two ID for here in the ID then where I can use for the ID okay.
So here I can already define for the list and now the stair I can select and execute you can see
here on the list completely so now just check and verify. So you can see here this is the list
and I can verify the companion table and now I can just select and it is filled and you can see
here the perfectly selected and delete from the row and the companion table and here the state
for the file table and the mark here not state for the pictures of that dress okay.
And then the name for the element okay and here the companion did a statement complete and here
I have it for perfectly review of the dating data from the post grade SQL table okay.
And I hope you perfectly found this tutorial helpful so stay tuned for more post real
SQL tips and kicks okay. So thank you for watching.